ARIEL MARTIN COHEN

DEVELOPER

+1 (438) 409-1041 | Montreal, QC

ariel.m.cohen@proton.me | ariel-cohen-portfolio.vercel.app

Education

DEC | Lasalle College, Montreal, QC **CS: Video Game Programming** 2021 - 2023

AEC | MCIT, Montreal, QC **CS: Full-Stack Java Web Dev.** 2020

DEP | ÉMAM, Montreal, QC **Aerospace Assembly Mechanic** 2012

Profile

I am a versatile developer that transitioned from a career in airplane mechanics and manufacturing to specialize in game development and web development. Knowledge with Unity and Unreal and front-end technologies like React with Tailwind, I bring a robust skill set to the table. My experience extends to back-end development with Java Spring and Express.JS with Typescript, alongside strong database management with MySQL and MongoDB. My previous roles in aerospace, including assembly, electro-mechanics, R&D methodologies, and quality control, have honed my problem solving skills and attention to detail, making me a valuable asset to any development team.

Technical Skills

Game Development:

- Unity
- Unreal, Blueprints

Languages:

- **♦** C#
- **♦** C++
- **❖** TypeScript
- Java
- Python

Front-End:

- React.JS, Next.JS
- ♦ HTML5, CSS3
- Tailwind

Back-End:

- ❖ Java SpringBoot
- Express, Hono
- Python Flask
- REST, RESTFul API

Database:

- ❖ SQL, MySQL
- NoSQL, MongoDB

General:

- . Git, Github
- ❖ VS Code
- NVIM
- Linux, Windows
- Docker

Experience

Front-End Developer

Logiciels Hadaly Inc. | Montreal, QC | May 2023 - March 2024

Developed and shipped two web applications from the ground up using Next.JS and Tailwind for their flagship products. Made use of services such as AWS EC2, Lambdas, and S3 Buckets, and GCC authentication. Showcased in person and in video form (<u>link to video</u>) to amass traction on the platform. I was the sole front-end developer on both projects. Aided in the development and deployment of the back-end, in Python FastAPI, into AWS Services.

Applications: www.hadaly.ca | www.tradeen.ai

Environment: Agile, React.JS, TypeScript, Python FastAPI, Git, Vercel, AWS, GC

Warehouse Clerk

Safran | Mirabel, QC | April 2019 - February 2020

Worked in the shipping and receiving for interior airplane parts. Our area needed to not only do warehouse stocking of items, but also assess integrity and quality of airplane parts and keep track of paperwork coming from different manufacturers. A keen eye for detecting imperfections and mismanaged paperwork was needed to properly do this task.

Environment: Forklift Certification, 5S Lean Manufacturing

Technician Assembler

Bühler Group | London, UK | April 2018 - April 2019

Assembly and testing of food sorting machines. Worked in tangent with R&D to create methodology of assembly for new products. Aided quality control for a new quality checking system that simplifies and keeps better track of work done by the assembler and QC.

Environment: Bühler 6S Lean Management

Production Worker

ABB Australia | Lilydale, VC, Australia | April 2017 - February 2018

Six months contract assembling and cabling High Voltage switches for electric facilities internationally. Learned to do cabling and other electrical work on various builds that were shipped from Canada to Singapore.

Environment: ABB Electric Security, Lean Management

Production Worker, Assembly Line Clerk

Pelican International | Laval, QC | June 2015 - May 2016

Assembly line clerk of kayaks and canoes. Directed and managed assemblies while keeping track of speed to reach daily quotas of assemblies.

Environment: 5S Lean Management

Hobbies and Activities

- Tutor kids with learning disabilities
- Hiking and trekking
- Video games and programming them
- Learning new technologies
- Motorsports and cars

Personal Projects

(ariel-cohen-portfolio.vercel.app)

- Shopping site showcasing my animations using pure JS and CSS
- Excel formatter for datasets
- Enemy AI in Unity with 2D NavMesh